Guide to the Charles McLean Andrews Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- MISCELLANEA, 1723-(1876-1967); Series VI; (3 boxes)
  - Biographical files
    - Labaree, Leonard Woods: "Charles McLean Andrews: Historian, 1863-1943," annotated by EWA, 1944 (Box 98, Folder 1029)
    - Riggs, John Beverley: "Charles McLean Andrews and the British Archives", 1949 (Box 98, Folder 1030)
    - Wright, Helen Martha: "Charles McLean Andrews: Interpreter of the Colonial Period in American History", 1944 (Box 98, Folder 1031)
    - Miscellaneous biographical material, mostly collected by EWA, 1932-1950 (Box 98, Folder 1032)
    - Papers re: the CMA Memorial Fellowship 1943-1944, undated (Box 98, Folder 1033)
  - Photographs
    General note
    See also: box 77, folders 934-937 box 91, folder 986 box 92, folder 992 box 99, folder 1036
    - Charles McLean Andrews and miscellanea, 1884-1933, undated (Box 98, Folder 1034)
  - Memorabilia
    - Essays in Colonial History Presented to Charles McLean Andrews by his Students: presentation copy, 1931 (Box 98, Folder 1035)
    - Charles McLean Andrews: photographs, undated (Box 99, Folder 1036)
    - Colonial documents, 1723-1774 (Box 99, Folder 1037)
    - Diplomas, certificates, honorary degrees, 1910-1943, undated (Box 99, Folder 1038-1039)
    - Walker, John Crawford: diploma, 1876 (Box 99, Folder 1040)
- Additional Material, 1761-1945; Accession 2016-M-060
  - Adams, Charles Francis, "The Sifted Grain and Grain Sifters", 1900 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - American Historical Association, "Annual Report of the Treasurer", 1936 October 31 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - American Philosophical Society, "Report from Recipients of Grants from the Research Funds", 1942 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Ames, Herman V., "The Amending Provision of the Federal Constitution in Practice", 1924 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Ames, Herman V., "Pennsylvania and the English Government 1699-1704", 1900 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Andrews, Charles M., "The Historian", 1924 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Asgill, John, "Several Associations Proved", Undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Baker-Crothes, Hayes and Ruth Alison Hudnut, "A Private Soldier's Account of Washington's First Battles in the West; A Study in Historical Criticism", 1942 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Baldwin, Simeon E., "The American Jurisdiction on the Bishop of London in Colonial Times", 1900 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Baldwin, Simeon E., "A Sketch of the Life of Rev. John Higginson, 1616-1708", 1903 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Banks, Charles Edward, "New Documents Relating to the Popham Expedition, 1607", 1930 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Bassett, John Spencer, "The Relation Between the Virginia Planter and the London Merchant", 1902 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Batchelder, Samuel F., "Burgoyne and his Officers in Cambridge 1777-1778", 1926 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Batchelder, Samuel F., "The Washington Elm Tradition. 'Under this Tree Washington First Took Command of the American Army' Is it True?", 1925 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Bates, Albert C., "Connecticut's Engraved Bills of Credit, 1709-1746", 1937 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Bates, Albert C., "The Connecticut Gore Land Company", 1899 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Bates, Albert C., "Thomas Green", 1913 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Bean, Walton E., "War and the British Colonial Farmer: A Reevaluation in the Light of New Statistical Records", 1942 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Beardsley, E. Edwards, "The Rev. Jeremiah Leaming, D.D.; His Life and Services", 1885 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Bell, Landon C., "The Era of National Disgrace, A Group Review", 1931 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Bell, Landon C., "The Era of National Disgrace, A Group Review", 1931 (Box 1, Folder 20a)
  - Benjamins, H.D. and Joh. F. Snelleman, "Encyclopædia van Nederlandsch West-Indië", 1914 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Bergen, Frank, "The Other Side of the Declaration of Independence", 1898 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Biggs, Charles Lewis, "William Leete, Co-founder of Guilford", 1940 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Bond, Beverly W., "The Colonial Agent as a Popular Representative", 1920 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Bond, Jr., Beverly W., "A Colonial Sidelight", 1911 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Boyd, Julian P., "Attempts to Form New States in New York and Pennsylvania, 1786-1796", 1931 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Boyd, J.P., "The Susquehannah Company, 1753-1803", 1931 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Bruce, Kathleen, "Virginian Agricultural Decline to 1860: A Fallacy", 1932 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Buffington, Arthur H., "The Policy of Albany and English Westward Expansion", 1922 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Carter, Clarence E., "The Beginnings of British West Florida", 1917 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Carter, Clarence E., "Observations of Superintendent John Stuart and Governor James Grant pof East Florida on the Proposed Plan of 1764 for the Future Management of Indian Affairs", 1915 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Carter, Clarence E., "The Significance of the Military Office in America, 1763-1775", 1923 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Carter, Clarence E., "Some Aspects of British Administration in West Florida", 1914 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Chandler, Charles Lyon, "Early Shipbuilding on the River Delaware", 1932 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Chapin, Howard Millar, "Roger Willians and the King's Colors; The Documentary Evidence", 1928 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Cheyney, Edward P., "Intellectual Freedom in a Democracy", 1936 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - "A Chronological Sketch of the Legislation from 1752 to 1884 on the Subject of Printing the Acts and Resolves of the Province of Massachusetts Bay", 1889 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Clark, Dora Mae, "The American Board of Customs, 1767-1783", 1940 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Connecticut Historical Society, "Connecticut Maps and Maps by Connecticut Engravers", 1935 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Connecticut Historical Society, "Examples of Connecticut Imprints of the Eighteenth Century", 1935 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Connecticut Historical Society, "List of Congregational Ecclesiastical Societies Established in Connecticut before October 1818 with their Changes", 1913 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Connecticut Historical Society, "List of Paintings and Miniatures", 1935 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Connecticut Historical Society, "Examples of Prints by Connecticut Artists and of Connecticut Subjects", 1935 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Connecticut Historical Society, "Publications by Connecticut Authors", 1935 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Connecticut Historical Society, "Connecticut Bills of Credit and Coins 1709-1788", 1935 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - "The Continental Congress", Undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Coolidge, Guy Omeron, "Biographical Index to the French Occupatiobn of the Champlain Valley from 1609-1759", 1938 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Crane, Verner W., "The Promotion Literature of Georgia", 1925 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Crane, Verner W., "A Lost Utopia of the First American Frontier", 1919 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Crane, Verner W., "Projects for Colonization in the South, 1684-1732", 1925 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Carter, William P., "The Ordinance of July 13, 1787 for the Government of the Territory Northwest of the River Ohio", 1887 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Darling, Charles W., "New Amsterdam, New Orange, New York; with Chronological Data", 1889 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Drell, Bernard, "John Taylor of Caroline and the Preservation of an Old Social Order", 1938 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Dulles, Charles W., "The Charity School of 1740, The Foundation of the University of Pennsylvania", 1904 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - The Enoch Pratt Free Library, "Contemporary Portraits of the Founder Proprietaries of Maryland", 1942 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Enoch Pratt Free Library, "The Lords Baltimore; A Collection of Portraits Loaned by Dr. Hugh H. Young; Displayed in the Central Hall" (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Ferguson, Henry, "Sir Edmund Andros", 1892 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Fox, Dixon Ryan, "Foundations of West India Policy", 1915 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Friedenwald, Herbert, "The Declaration of Independence", 1901 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Gipson, Lawrence Henry, "Acadia and the Beginnings of Modern British Imperialism", 1941 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Gipson, Lawrence H., "Charles McLean Andrews and the Re-orientation of the Study of American Colonial history", 1935 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Gipson, Lawrence Henry, "'Some Reflections upon the American Revolution' and other Essays in American Colonial History", 1942 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Gould, Clarence P., "Trade Between the Windward Islands and the Continental Colonies of the French Empire, 1683-1763", 1939 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Grant, W.L., "The Colonial Policy of Chatham", 1911 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Hacker, Louis Marton, "The First American Revolution", 1935 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Hanley, Miles L., "Dialect Notes, Vol. VI, Part III", 1931 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Hanley, Miles L., "Dialect Notes, Vol. VI, Part IV", 1932 July (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Hanley, Miles L., "Dialect Notes, Vol. VI, Part V", 1932 December (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Haring, C.H., "Ledgers of the Royal Treasurers in Spanish America in the Sixteenth Century", 1919 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Harper, Lawrence A., "Mercantilism and the American Revolution", 1942 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Harrey, D.C., "Machias and the Invasion of Nova Scotia", 1932 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Harte, Charles Rufus, "Connecticut's Canals", 1938 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Harwood, Edwin, "The Beginnings of the Episcopal Church in New Haven; A Discourse Delivered in Trinity Church, New Haven", 1894 December 30 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - The Hayes Foundation, "The Hayes Memorial Library, Fourth Annual Report 1940-41", 1941 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Hayes, I. Minis, "On the Authorship of the anonymous Pamphlet Published in London in 1760 Entitled 'The Interest of Great Britain Considered with Regard to Her Colonies and the Acquisition of Canada and Guadaloupe'", 1924 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Henderson, Archibald, "The Founding of Nashville, Second of the Transylvania Towns; Boonesboro, KY, Nashville, TN, Henderson, KY", 1932 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Henderson, Archibald, "Hermon Husband's Continuation (1770) of the Impartial Relation", 1941 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Henderson, Archibald, "The Significance of the Transylvania Company in American History", 1935 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Higham, C.S.S., "The Genreal Assembly of the Leeward Islands", 1926 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Hirsch, Elizabeth F., "John Cotton and Roger Williams: Their Controversy Concerning Religious Liberty", 1941 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Holmes, Thomas J., "Cotton Mather and his Writings on Witchcraft", 1936 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Insh, George Pratt, "The Founders of the Company of Scotland", 1928 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Jenkins, Charles F., "The Completed Sets of the Signers of the Declaration of Independece", 1925 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Jennings, John J., "Centennial Celebration of the Incorporation of the town of Bristol, June 17, 1885", 1995 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Jernegan, Marcus W., "Compulsory Education in the American Colonies" (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Jernegan, Marcus W., "Slavery and the Beginnings of Industrialism in the American Colonies", 1920 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Jernegan, Marcus W., "Slavery and Conversion in the American Colonies", 1916 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Johnson, Cecil, "A Note on Absenteeism and Pluralism in British West Florida", 1936 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Johnson, Cecil, "Expansion in West Florida", 1934 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - "Journal of the Siege of York-town", 1931 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Keith, Herbet C. and Charles Rufus Harte, "The Early Iron Industry of Connecticut" (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Kirby, Ephraim, "Reports of Cases Adjudged in the Superior Court of the State of Connecticut", 1933 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Klingberg, Frank J., "The Anglican Minority in Colonial Pennsylvania, with Particular Reference to the Indian", 1941 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Klingberg, Frank J., "The Evolution of the Humanitarian Spirit in Eighteenth Century England", 1942 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Klingberg, Frank J., "The Lady Mico Charity Schools in the British West Indies, 1835-1842", 1939 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Klingberg, Frank J., "Philip Quaque: Pioneer Native Missionary on the Gold Coast, 1765-1816", 1939 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Kohler, Max J., "Jewish Activity in American Colonial Commerce", 1902 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Kohler, Max J., "A Memorial of Jews to Parliament Concerning Jewsih Participation in Colonial Trade, 1696", 1909 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Laprade, W.T., "The Present State of the History of England in the Eighteeneth Century", 1932 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Lincoln, Charles Henry, "A Calendar of the Manuscripts of Col. John Bradsheet in the Library of the Society", 1908 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Lincoln, Charles Henry, "The Journal of Sir William Pepperrell Kept During the Expedition Agaisnt Louisburg, Mar. 24-Aug. 22, 1745", 1910 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Lingelbach, Anna Lane, "The Inception of the British Board of Trade", 1925 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Larrabee, Don Marshall, "A Reprint of the Journal of George Washington, and that of his Guide Christopher Gist, reciting their Experiences on the Historic Mission from Governor Dinwiddie, of Virginia, to the French Commandant at Fort Le Boeuf om November-December, 1753", 1924 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Mark, Irving, "Agrarian Conflicts in New York and the American Revolution", 1942 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Marsden, R.G., "The High Court of Admiralty in Relation to National History, Commerce and the Colonisation of America--AD 1550-1650", 1902 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Mather, Cotton, "The Tryal of Susana Martin; At the Court of Oyer and Terminer, held by Adjournment at Salem, June 30, 1692", Undated (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Matthews, Albert, "Journal of William Loughton Smith 1790-1791", 1914 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - McCulloh, H., "Our Concerns in America", 1761 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - McLaughlin, Andrew C., "The Background of American Federalism", 1918 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Merriman, Roger B., "Some Notes on the Treatment of the English Catholics in the Reign of Elizabeth", 1908 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Morgan, Forrest, "Connecticut's 'Warwick Patent', Solution of a Historic Mystery", 1910 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Morgan, William Thomas, "The British West Indies During King William's War (1689-97)", 1930 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Morgan, William Thomas, "English Fear if 'Encirclement' in the Seventeenth Century", 1928 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Morgan, William Thomas, "The Five Nations and Queen Anne", 1926 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Morgan, William Thomas, "The Origins of the South Sea Company", 1929 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Morgan, William Thomas, "Queen Anne's Canadian Expedition of 1711", 1928 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Morgan, William Thomas, "The South Sea Company and the Canadian Expedition in the Reign of Queen Anne", 1928 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Morison, Samuel Eliot, "Dr. Morison's Address; November 21st, 1935", 1936 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Morison, S.E., "A Prologue to American History", 1922 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Morris, Richard B., "Criminal Conspiracy and Early Labor Combinations in New York", 1937 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Morris, Richard B., "Judicial Supremacy and the Inferior Courts on the American Colonies", 1940 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Morse, Jarris M., "John Smith and his Critics: A Chapter in Colonial Historiography", 1935 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - National Archives, "The Care of Records in a National Emergency", 1941 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Nettles, Curtis, "The Beginnings of Money in Connecticut", 1928 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Nettles, Curtis, "British Payments in the American Colonies, 1685-1715", 1933 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Nettles, Curtis, "British Policy and Colonial Money Supply" (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Nettles, Curtis, "The Economic Relations of Boston, Philadelphia and New York, 1680-1715", 1931 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Nettles, Curtis, "England and the Spanish-American Trade, 1680-1715", 1931 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Nettles, Curtis, "The Origins of Paper Money in English Colonies", 1934 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Otto, Par Louis-Guillaume, "Considérations sur la conduite du Gouvernement Américain envers la France", 1945 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Palmer, Charles Ray, "Rev. William Jooke, 1601-1678", 1912 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Parish, John Carl, "The Intrigues of Doctor James O'Fallon", 1930 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Parker Son Ltd., "Catalogue of Secondhand Old and Modern Editions of Greek Latin Authors", Undated (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Pennington, Edgar Legare, "The Church of England in Colonial North Carolina", 1937 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Pennington, Edgar Legare, "The Church of England in Colinial Virginia", 1937 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Pennington, Edgar Legare, "The Church of England in Colonial Virginia, Part II", 1937 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Pennington, Edgar Legare, "The Church of England in Early Colonial New Hampshrire and the Revered Arthur Browne", 1937–1938 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Pennington, Edgar Legare, "The Episcopal Church in Florida, 1763-1892", 1938 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Pennington, Edgar Legare, "Nathaniel Evans, A Poet of Colonial America", 1935 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Phillips, James Duncan, "British Depredations in the West Indies; Especially the Salem Vessels Libelled in Jamaica in 1794", 1942 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Phillips, James Duncan, "The Routine Trade of Salem Under the Confederation Congress May 1783-October 1789", 1941 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Pierson, William Whatley, "Some Reflections on the Cabildo as an Institution", 1922 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Pittman, R. Carter, "The Colonial and Constitutional History of the Privilege Against Self-Incrimination in America", 1935 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Porter, Noah, "The New England Meeting House", 1883 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Preston, Howard W., "Washignton's Visits to Rhode Island, gathered from Contemporary Accounts", 1932 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Putnam Co., "Connecticut; her Constitutions", 1935 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Ragatz, Lowell Joseph, "A List of Books and Articles on Colonial History and Overseas Expansion Published in the United States in 1931 and 1932", Undated (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - "Records of the Particular Court of the Colony of Connecticut; Administration of Sir Edmond Andros, Royalo Governor, 1687-1688", 1935 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Reynolds, Charles B., "The Landing of Ponce de Leon; A Historical Review", 1934 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Rice, Franklin P., "Records of the Proprietors of Worcester, Massachusetts", 1881 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Root, Winfred Trexler, "The American Revolution Reconsidered", 1942 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Roscher, Wilhelm, "The Spanish Colonial System", 1904 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Rosengarten, J.G., "Archenwall's Observations on North America, 1767", 1903 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - "Rufus Putnam: A Massachusetts Empire Builder", Undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Schuyler, Robert Livingston, "The Britannic Question and the American Revolution", 1923 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Seymour, George D., "The English Home and Ancestry of Richard Seamer or Semer of Hartford, Conn., Progenitor of the Seymours of Connecticut and New York", 1917 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Seymour, George Dudley, "Memorials of Theophilus Eaton, First Governor of the New Haven Colony", 1938 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Seymour, George Dudley, "Researches of an Antiquary; Five Essays on Ameican Architects" (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Shepard, James, "John Hall of Wallingford, Conn.", 1902 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Siebert, W.H., "The Exodus of the Loyalists from Penobscot and the Loyalist Settlements at Passamaquoddy", 1914 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Sioussat, George L., "The Breakdown of the Royal Management of Lands in the Southern Provinces, 1773-1775", 1929 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Sioussat, St. George L., "The Chevalier de la Luzerne and the Ratification of the Articles of Confederation by Maryland, 1780-1781", 1936 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Sioussat, St. George Leakin, "The North Carolina Cession of 1784 in Its Federal Aspects", 1909 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Sioussat, St. George Leakin, "Virginia and the English Commercial System 1730-1733", 1906 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Spencer, Charles Worthen, "Sectional Aspects of New York Provincial Politics", 1915 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Stearns, Raymond Phineas, "The Production of Sugar in Barbados c. 1667", 1936 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Steiner, Bernard C., "Rev. Thomas Bray and his American Libraries", Undated (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Steiner, Walter R., "Dr. James Thatcher of Plymouth, Massachusetts, an Erudite Physician of Revolutionary and Post-Revolutionarty Fame", 1933 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Stock, Leo Francis, "The Irish Parliament and the American Revolution", 1939 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Tatum, Edward H., "Ambrose Serle, Secretary to Lord Howe, 1776-1778", 1939 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Tercentenary Commission of the State of Connecticut, "The Tercentenary of Connecticut", 1935 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Thoms, Herbert, "The Beginnings of Medical Practice in New Haven Colony", 1924 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Turner, Edward Raymond, "Committees of Council and the Cabinet, 1660-1688", 1914 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Turner, Edward Raymond, "The Development of the Cabinet 1688-1760", 1913 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Turner, Edward Raymond, "The Lords Justices of England 1695-1755", 1914 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Turner, Edward Raymond, "The Materials for the Study of the English Cabinet in the Eighteeneth Century", 1913 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Turner, Raymond, "The Origin of the Cabinet Council", 1923 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Tyler, Lyon G., "The Original Counties", 1934 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Usher, Ronald G., "The Institutional History of the House of Commons 1547-1641", 1924 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Volwiler, Albert T., "George Crogham and the Westward Movement, 1741-1782", 1922 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Walker, Williston, "The Influence of the Mathers in New England Religious Development", 1893 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Walker, Williston, "Why did not Massachusetts have a Saybrook Platform?", 1892 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Waring, Martha Gallaudet, "Savannah's Earliest Private Schools", Undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Weeden, William B., "Three Commonwealths, Massachusetts, Connecticut and Rhode Island; Their Early Developments", 1903 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Welles, Edwin Stanley, "The Beginnings of Fruit Culture in Connecticut", 1936 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Welles, Lemuel A., "The English Ancestry of Gov. Thomas Welles of Connecticut", 1926 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Wertenbaker, T.J., "The Founding of American Civilisation", 1936 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Westergaard, Walderman Christian, "A St. Croix Map of 1766: With a Note on its Significance in West Indian Plantation Economy", 1938 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Whitson, Agnes, "The outlook of the Continental American Colonies on the British West Indies, 1760-1775", 1930 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Williams, Justin, "English Mercantilism and Carolina Naval States, 1705-1776", 1935 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Wright, Irene, "The English Conquest of Jamaica", 1923 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Wright, I.A., "Spanish Narratives of the English Attack on Santo Domingo 1655", 1926 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Wright, Irene A., "The Spanish Resistance to the English Occupation of Jamaica, 1655-1660, Based Upon Contemporary Documents in the Archives of the Indies, Seville, Spain", 1930 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Wroth, Lawrence C., "Source Materials of Florida History in the John Carter Brown Library of Brown University", 1941 (Box 7, Folder 17)